In the cybersecurity world,
a security analyst received thousands of alerts a day.
Now, when they investigate,
most of them are actually noises and some of them are a real attack.
Missing one of those could actually lead to
a security incident through a business where there could be a data breach.
I created an agent which actually help
a security or a human analyst to investigate the alert automatically.
Provide a response in a strict structure,
evidence, contradiction, any missing information,
and what is the recommended step or an action
which analysts should perform and confidence.
If we wanted to an investigation,
we'll select which event we want to investigate,
click on it, and do a triage.
There's already two of the events which are already triaged.
If you look at it,
one of the incident where it says credential trip,
it investigated and found out that it needs to be escalated as a P1.
It will give you all the key evidence,
what it did find.
It will give you a clear structure of the evidence,
the contradiction, anything missing,
or the recommended actions.
If you go down, it will actually map it to a Miter Attack Framework,
which is a industry standard for
cybersecurity behavior for the attackers.
Then it will give you a score breakdown like why it did score it as 100.
It will give you a proper trail of decision,
which gives it AI transparency for a human to understand.
Along with that, it will give a narrative and
a incident ticket draft which analysts can use for a ticketing purpose.
Since we are using AI agents everywhere in different department,
I also included an option where if it detects an injection,
it should block that.
As you can see, one of the event had a command where it was trying to instruct
the agent to stop treating this event as an attack and put it as a non-suspicious.
As you can see, it find the key evidence,
but ignored it, it still investigated,
mapped it up, and then there's also an option for enrichment,
where basically it is enriching from different open source intelligence.
This is not an AI making an uncontrollable security decision.
The agent investigate and recommends.
The human analysts actually control the operational response,
so the AI responses, the rule will decide what it needs to be done,
and the analyst would act on it. Thank you.